https://southwell.anglican.org/privacy-notice/

THE DIOCESE OF SOUTHWELL AND NOTTINGHAM
Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
Who are we?
The Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham is the data controller (contact details below). This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
How do we process your personal data?
The Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by: –
keeping personal data up to date;
by storing and destroying it securely;
by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data;
by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure; and
by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: –
To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public within the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham;
To administer records of: –
Clergy;
Lay Readers;
Pastoral Assistants
Pioneers
DCC & PCC Officers
Eucharistic Ministers (who are authorised to assist with the Chalice at Holy Communion)
General, Diocesan & Deanery Synod members
Cathedral, DBF and DBE Committees
To fundraise and promote the interests of the Diocese;
To manage our employees and volunteers;
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running either within the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham or further afield through: –
Mailings (by email &/or hard copy)
Email Communications (Weekly Update) (a subscription email service from which you can unsubscribe at any time)
What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about diocesan events;
Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –
the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent except as set out set out in 5 below
Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared within the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham, in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the Diocese, and certain third parties outside of the Diocese as set out in Annex A.
How long do we keep your personal data?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Save or Delete: the Care of Diocesan Records” which is available from the Church of England website at https://www.churchofengland.org/more/libraries-and-archives/records-management-guides.
Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –
The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham holds about you;
The right to request that the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time
The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability).
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable);
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.
Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Director of Parish Support at the a below address, telephone number: 01636 814331 or fraser@southwell.anglican.org. Alternatively, you can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
Annex A
Third parties with whom data will be shared: –
The Diocesan Database is a shared resource between: –
The office of the Bishop of Southwell and Nottingham
The Archdeacon of Nottingham
The Archdeacon of Newark
The Chancellor for the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham
The Diocesan Board of Finance
Southwell and Nottingham Multi Academy Trust
The office of the Diocesan Registrar
The clergy and DCC / PCC officers within the Diocese
The Church of England National Church Institutions
The contact details of Petitioners and/or applicants on individual applications will be shared, through the Online Faculty System (OFS): –
The Archdeacon of Nottingham
The Archdeacon of Newark
The Chancellor for the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham
The Deputy Chancellor for the Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham
The office of the Diocesan Registrar
The DAC Committee, a current list of members can be found here https://goo.gl/sHdqFr
The DAC Advisers, a current list of advisers can be found here https://goo.gl/sHdqFr
Statutory Consultees (The Church Buildings Council, Historic England, national Amenity Societies and local authorities)
to facilitate the consideration of applications for either a Faculty or a Matter not requiring a Faculty under the Faculty Jurisdiction Rules
Clergy contact details will be provided: –
Periodically to Crockford’s Clerical Directory
The Church of England National Church Institutions
When necessary, by the Diocesan Property Team to its representatives for the purpose of undertaking works of repair / maintenance of Cathedral / Diocesan clergy housing and the letting of Diocesan properties
To the relevant local authority (in respect of Council Tax) and utility companies (in respect of supplies of energy to the property
To the relevant Pension Providers
In compliance with our legal responsibilities
The Church of England across Nottinghamshire
Growing Disciples Wider Younger Deeper
The Southwell & Nottingham Diocesan Synod and Board of Finance. A charitable company limited by guarantee: Company No 34165 England, Charity No 249359
Copyright 2013 Diocese of Southwell and Nottingham
This site uses cookies Tell me more about cookies.That's OK.
